# Angshuman Mazumdar

I believe in a simple concept: if it's a piece of engineering, it is also a work of art. Also, an ardent follower of interactive media, especially video games, because they provide a great platform for experiences to flourish, unlike any other media.



angshuman.mazumdar@gmail.com



West Lafayette, Indiana



https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/

(585)-406-9165

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/angshuman-mazumdar-a0b75a130/

(O) https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/portfolio

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Capstone Project**

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester (New York) January 2019 – May 2019

### **Bachelor of Technology (Electronics and Communication)**

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore 2015 - 2019 (CGPA - 8.69)

#### **High School and Senior School**

Don Bosco Senior Secondary School, Guwahati 2003 - 2015 (93.4%)

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Trainee**

Bharti Airtel 05/2018 - 06/2018 Chandigarh, India Achievements/Tasks

- Automated data collection and organization process for SACFA Applicants (using Visual Basic for Applications) which reduced the time for data organization significantly.
- Worked on collecting the azimuth data for various sites for towers using their latitude and longitude.
- Worked on "Project Junoon" by daily updating new sites on the maps, filtering out the sites with maximum problems, and categorizing the different sites.

# **Graphic Designer**

MOX - Movement of Expression 02/2018 - 08/2019

Shillong, India

An organization that caters to services such as Event Management, Talent Management, PR, Photography, as well as hosting various events around India

Achievements/Tasks

Designed the logos for the event "Street Sangam".

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

**Design Head (BEAM-VIT)** (06/2016 – 05/2017)

BEAM-VIT was a club of VIT University

## **Design Co-Chair (BIDSF'17)** (01/2017 – 04/2017)

BIDSF is an annual event organized by the Biotech Division of VIT with the help of various clubs. Responsibilities included creating the theme, logo, posters and oversee various other design related issues for the event.

#### Design Advisor for Team Vimaanas (01/2017 - 06/2018)

Team Vimaanas is the official Micro-Class RC Aviation team of VIT. Responsibilities included helping them out with their design team by organizing their workflow, as well as teaching the members about graphic design, and redesigning their brochure.

#### **SKILLS**

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe Premiere Pro Unreal Engine 4 Unity3D World Machine Autodesk Maya Autodesk 3DS Max Blender SketchUp NukeX C++HTML and CSS

Microsoft Office Suite (PowerPoint, Word, Excel)

### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

## Parkinson's Disease Assist Device using Machine Learning and Internet of Things (07/2017 - 04/2018)

- The main purpose of the project was to construct a prototype of a spoon which senses the hand motion of an individual suffering from Parkinson's disease.
- It gives a counter motion to the trembling actions of a patient's hand, in order that they don't spill their food.
- Machine Learning is used to detect any anomalies in the sensor data from the device. If an anomaly is detected the device send a mail alert to the well-wishers of the patient.

#### **Autonomous Robotic Manipulator** (01/2019 – 04/2019)

- The goal was to develop the driver that will control a robotic
- Oversaw the robotic arm manipulation of the larger project
- Final objective was to mount the arm to the top of an autonomous base, that could enable users to control it using Virtual Reality Techniques
- Application in the Elder Care Industry
- Core skills learned: setting up drivers for a controller (here specifically it was the OpencM9.04 Control board), interfaced hardware motors with a software controller, basics of realtime interaction using virtual reality techniques.

# **LANGUAGES**



"Design and technology go hand in hand – sometimes you design to innovate, while other times innovation leads to new design philosophies."